# SCOTT GELEAS

### Alton, NH 03809

Phone: (603)-455-1657 | Email: scottgeleas97@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/scottgeleas | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/scottgeleas/

Portfolio: https://scottgeleas.github.io/React-Portfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Web Developer bringing experience in teamwork, multitasking, and attention to detail. Group-minded, with a focus on completing tasks to ensure objectives are always met. Recently completed a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from University of New Hampshire, where experience was gained working in small groups to create professional-looking applications that developed a variety of technical skills and concepts. Have been recognized two times in a previous role for the work quality and performance (5-Star Supplier Excellence Award).

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, SQL, NoSQL, CSS3, HTML5,

Applications: GitHub, Heroku, Insomnia, Robo 3T, MongoDB Atlas, MySQL Workbench, Windows

Tools: React.js, GraphQL, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Jest

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Restful Cabin Retreats**

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Restful-Cabin-Retreats https://restful-cabin-retreats-sjg.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A full stack web application that allows users to 'rent' cabins from around the world. Users have the ability to 'reserve' a cabin after a user has created an account. A MySQL database was used with Sequelize to store the data needed.
- Role: Back-end Database Modeling and Routes
- Tools: Node.js, Express.js, SQL, Sequelize, MySQL Workbench, Handlebars.js, and Flatpickr.js.

#### Reciflixor

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Reciflixorhttps://scottgeleas.github.io/Reciflixor/

- Summary: An application where movie lovers can select a movie and enjoy a recipe from that movie to experience the world the directors created. This was created with the YouTube API and the OMDb API
- Role: Back-end queries with API's and general JavaScript logic.
- Tools: HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.

## **Healthy Mongoose**

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Reciflixorhttps://scottgeleas.github.io/Reciflixor/

- Summary: A web app that allows users to keep track of their fitness goals. Users input workout type, duration and/or weight lifted. After they are presented with their total workout time for the past seven days.
- Role: Back end logic using Mongoose as the ORM.
- Tools: JavaScript, Mongoose, MongoDB, Robo 3T, MongoDB Atlas, Node.js.

#### **Progressive Budget Tracker**

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Progressive-Budget-Tracker https://progressive-budget-tracker-sig.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A progressive web app utilizing an IndexedDB to store user data when the user is not connected to the internet. After returning online the application will push the offline data to the database.
- Role: IndexedDB, manifest, service worker and database...
- Tools: IndexedDB, JavaScript, Mongoose, MongoDB, Robo 3T, MongoDB Atlas, Node.js.

#### **Note Taker**

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Note-Takerhttps://note-taker-sig.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A simple application allowing users to create notes. Simply type a note, give it a title, and add it with the + button.
- Role: CRUD with Express Routes.
- Tools: Express.js, JavaScript, Node.js.

#### EXPERIENCE

# Mechanical Assembler Milpower Source

2017 – 2020

Belmont, NH

Responsible for receiving and inventorying incoming products. Utilizing teamwork and various tools to assemble power supplies. Testing finished products, labeling, and packaging them for shipment. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- 5-Star Supplier Excellence Award from Raytheon 2019 & 2020
- Inventoried and built products to ensure they were delivered on time and in the correct quantities.
- Contributed to a team of five by moving products and jumping in to accomplish any other team goals that needed to be met on a daily basis.

# Laborer Currier Construction Remodeling

2016 - 2017 Farmington, NH

Responsible for keeping product handy for workers to grab and go, keeping jobsite clean, and minor

Key Accomplishments:

construction duties.

- Ensured worker safety by setting up staging and ladders in specific locations on the jobsite.
- Kept jobsites clean which resulted in higher customer satisfaction.

#### PART-TIME/SEASONAL

Delivery Driver 2014 - 2015 Patriot Pizza Barnstead, NH

Lake Host 2014 - 2014
New Hampshire Lakes Association Wolfeboro, NH

Prep Cook 2012 - 2014
Pop's Clam Shell Alton, NH

#### EDUCATION

### Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate | August 2021

University of New Hampshire, Durham, NH

A 6-month program for Full Stack Web Development. Utilizing continuous learning of technical programming skills including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, Handelbars.js, React.js, GraphQL, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, jQuery, & Bootstrap among other technologies and frameworks.